Guide to the James Ludovic Lindsay collection of French manuscripts, 1767-1863
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
- Manuscripts with the Bibliotheca Lindesiana bookplate, 1792-1835, (4 boxes)
  - Letter from Rossollin to the Count of Sussy, 1812 Jan. 20 (Box 2, Folder 91)
    Petition from Rossollin to Sussy asking for a job in the Commerce Ministry.
  - Letter from Gobert to the Minister of Commerce, 1812 Jan. 20 (Box 2, Folder 92)
    Petition from Gobert seeking a position.
  - Letter from Ladoucette, prefect of Roer, 1812 Jan. 20 (Box 2, Folder 93)
    Ladoucette congratulates the person to whom he is writing.
  - Letter from the Count of Segur to the Count of Sussy, 1812 Jan. 21 (Box 2, Folder 94)
    Segur explains to Sussy that the person bringing him this letter would like to see him and perhaps become his valet.
  - Letter from Girardin to the Count of Sussy, 1812 Feb. 3 (Box 2, Folder 95)
    Girardin (speaking in the third person) explains in his letter to the Count that he is recommending a person born in the same town at H.R.H. the Queen of Spain and has been asked by her to recommend this person as best he can.
  - Letter from Routhier to the Commerce Minister, 1812 Jan. 21 (Box 2, Folder 96)
    Routhier flatters the Minister and asks to see him briefly once more.
  - Letter from Dujardin-Sailly, 1812 Jan. 21 (Box 2, Folder 97)
    Dujardin-Sailly congratulates the person to whom he is writing and insinuates that he wants a job.
  - Letter from J.M. De Gerando to the Count (Sussy?), 1812 Jan. 22 (Box 2, Folder 98)
    De Gerando conveys Mr. Miollis' situation and wishes to the Count.
  - Letter from Jerome Octave Dania to the Count of Sussy, Minister of Commerce and Manufacturing, 1812 Jan. 22 (Box 2, Folder 99)
    Dania petitions for a job.
  - Letter from J.M. De Gerando to the Count (Sussy?), 1812 Jan. 22 (Box 2, Folder 100)
    De Gerando writes a recommendation for Mr. Deseroizilles.
  - Letter from Mollien to the Count of Sussy, 1812 Jan. 23 (Box 2, Folder 101)
    Mollien informs Sussy that S. Paillet would like to meet him.
  - Letter from Jacques Grouvel to the Count of Sussy, Minister of Commerce and Manufacturing, 1812 Jan. 23 (Box 2, Folder 102)
    Grouvel writes seeking a position.
  - Letter from Labrouste to the Minister of Commerce and Manufacturing, 1812 Jan. 23 (Box 2, Folder 103)
    Labrouste asks Sussy for a job for his nephew.
  - Letter from Du-Bois-Du Bais, Senator, Count of the Empire to Count Collin of Sussy, 1812 Jan. 24 (Box 2, Folder 104)
    Du-Bois-Du Bais sends Sussy a petition for a young man, hoping to find him a job.
  - Letter from Montalivet to the Count of Sussy, 1812 Jan. 24 (Box 2, Folder 105)
    Montaliver recommends a person to work at the Ministry.
  - Letter from Charles Raut to the Count of Sussy, 1812 Jan. 25 (Box 2, Folder 106)
    Raut writes a petition for himself, requesting a job.
  - Letter from D'Arlincourt to the Minister of Commerce and Manufacturing, 1812 Jan. 25 (Box 2, Folder 107)
    D'Arlincourt congratulates Sussy on his new position
  - Letter from the Count of D'Hauterive to the Count of Sussy, 1812 Jan. 26 (Box 2, Folder 108)
    The Count of D'Hauterive writes a petition for M. Farcot, hoping to find him a job.
  - Letter from Charles Pougens to Count Collin of Sussy, 1812 Jan. 27 (Box 2, Folder 109)
    Pougens, who does not personally know the Count, sends him a letter emphasizing his experience and requesting a position.
  - Petition from G.P. Valeton to the Minister of Commerce and Manufacturing, Count Collin of Sussy, 1812 Jan. 27 (Box 2, Folder 110)
    Valeton writes a petition, requesting a job.
  - Petition from Da Costa La Seroniere to Collin de Sussy, 1812 Jan. 27 (Box 2, Folder 111)
    Da Costa La Seroniere writes a petition requesting a job.
  - Petition from Dumont, lawyer, to the Count of Sussy, 1812 Jan. 27 (Box 2, Folder 112)
    Dumont requests a job.
  - Petition from Charles Jean-Baptiste Bryard to HRH the Emperor and King, 1812 Jan. 28 (Box 2, Folder 113)
    Bryard offers his services to HR Majesty.
  - Petition from Boucard to the Count of Sussy, 1812 Jan. 29 (Box 2, Folder 114)
    Petition from Boucard for Leger. Requests a job for him.
  - Petition from Marescalchi to Count of Sussy, 1812 Jan. 29 (Box 2, Folder 115)
    Petition from Marescalchi for Mr. Viollet, requesting a job.
  - Letter from Count Daru to Monsieur Parisse, 1812 Jan. 31 (Box 2, Folder 116)
    The count Daru explains to Mr. Parisse that he has received both his letter and the letter destined to Count Sussy, and he will recommend him to the Count Sussy the next time he sees him, in order for Parisse to get the job he desires.
  - Letter from Supervielle (son) to the Count of Sussy, 1812 Jan. 31 (Box 2, Folder 117)
    Supervielle explains his current financial situation, and asks the Count to give him a job, since he is married and about to become a father.
  - Petition from Fabre De L'Aude, 1812 Feb. 1 (Box 3, Folder 118)
    Petition from De L'Aude regarding Mr. Dupont (of Lyon), requesting a job.
  - Letter from Ph. Lancel to Count of Sussy, Minister of Commerce and State Advisor, 1812 Feb. 1 (Box 3, Folder 119)
    Lancel writes to the Count of Sussy, explaining his many titles in hope of working with him in his office.
  - Letter from Emmery, a knight and deputy of the North Region to the Count of Sussy, Minister of Commerce, 1812 Feb. 1 (Box 3, Folder 120)
    Emmery recommends Lancel to Sussy, simply stating that he deserves both the goodwill and protection from the Count.
  - Letter from Count Joseph Caffarelli to the Count of Sussy, 1812 Feb. 1 (Box 3, Folder 121)
    Caffarelli recommends Mr. Sol for a job in the Ministry of Commerce.
  - Letter from Count François Jaubert, 1812 Feb. 1 (Box 3, Folder 122)
    Jaubert thanks "the Count" (probably Count Sussy) for nominating Mr. Soubiran for a new post.
  - Document on the state of the service of Mr. Bruni from Chabrol, 1812 Feb. 2 (Box 3, Folder 123)
    A sort of recommendation stating the quality of Mr. Bruni's services, followed by observations by Chabrol. Chabrol is requesting a job for Mr. Ferdinand Bruni.
  - Petition from Gabriel Briand to Count of Sussy, 1812 Feb. 3 (Box 3, Folder 124)
    Briand petitions for a position at the Ministry of Commerce.
  - Petition from Borel to Sussy, 1812 Feb. 6 (Box 3, Folder 125)
    Borel requests a job at the ministry of Commerce.
  - Petition from Marquis de Montferrier du Vidal to Sussy, 1812 Feb. 7 (Box 3, Folder 126)
    Vidal forwards a petition previously written by Mr. Potier about his nephew, Mr. Lovznoze, requesting a job at the Ministry of Commerce.
  - Letter from Routhier to the Commerce Minister, 1812 Feb. 12 (Box 3, Folder 127)
    Routhier writes to Sussy about a job.
  - Petition from Claude François Rabusson to Sussy, 1812 Feb. 12 (Box 3, Folder 128)
    Rabusson recommends himself for a job at the Ministry.
  - Petition from Bonnefoux to Sussy, 1812 Feb. 14 (Box 3, Folder 129)
    Bonnefoux recommends Mr. David for a job at Ministry
  - Petition from the Petition Commision to the Minister of Manufacturing (Sussy), 1812 Feb. 15 (Box 3, Folder 130)
    The Commision asks the Count if he has received the petition regarding Mr. S. Bruyard.
  - Petition from Jean Chapus to the Count of Sussy, 1812 Feb. 15 (Box 3, Folder 131)
    Chapus writes his own recommendation.
  - Letter from Prefect J.P. Chazel to the General Director of Customs, 1812 Feb. 16 (Box 3, Folder 132)
    Chazal forwards a letter from the vice-prefect to the General Director.
  - Petition from Nicolas François Loree to the Minister of Commerce, 1812 Feb. 29 (Box 3, Folder 133)
    Loree writes asking for a job.
  - Letter from Chaban to Le Grand, 1812 Mar. 3 (Box 3, Folder 134)
    Chaban writes to Le Grand, Minister of Finance about a miscommunication that happened with the nomination
  - Letter from V. Vansittart to d'Antraigues, 1812 Mar. 9 (Box 3, Folder 135)
    Vansittart writes to the Count, discussing his health and forwarding letters that he has received.
  - Letter from Count Moreton-Chabrillion to the Interior Minister, 1812 Mar. 28 (Box 3, Folder 136)
    Count Moreton-Chabrillion writes a letter of recommendation for Favre.
  - Letter from De Joly to De Beaumont, 1812 April 17 (Box 3, Folder 137)
    De Joly explains he will not be able to attend the assembly on Monday and gives his opinion on an issue that divides the assembly: a momentary mistake should not be punished as if it were a horrible mistake.
  - Petition from Jaubert to Count de Sussy, 1812 May 5 (Box 3, Folder 138)
    Jaubert recommends Pierre D'Esparbes for a job.
  - Letter from Collet-Des Costils to the General Director of Customs, 1812 Jun. 1 (Box 3, Folder 139)
    Collet-Des Costils thanks the Director for the letter he received and informs him that he also received the legal statement regarding the theft of 17 pots.
  - Letter from Chabrol to Mr. Dizie, 1812 Jun. 5 (Box 3, Folder 140)
    Count Chabrol explains that the Borata (a ship) has left Tieste with a shipment of salt.
  - Letter from Vansittart to d'Antraigues (the son), 1812 Aug. 13 (Box 3, Folder 141)
    Vansittart explains that he will not be able to meet with the Count on the day they had appointed.
  - Letter from La Rochefoucauld to Mr. Jecker, 1812 Sept. 14 (Box 3, Folder 142)
    La Rouchefoucauld recommends a young man for a job
  - Letter from the Baron Girod de l'Ain to the person in charge of the general administration, 1812 Sept. 21 (Box 3, Folder 143)
    The Baron recommends a job for the Director of Vervis.
  - Petition from De Gregory de Marcorengo to the Count of Sussy, 1812 Sept. 25 (Box 3, Folder 144)
    De Gregory recommends Mr. Morel for a job.
  - Letter from Corvisart to Mr. Godine, 1812 Sept. 29 (Box 3, Folder 145)
    Corvisart invites Mr. Godine for dinner.
  - Letter from Bernard Journu-Aubert, Senator, to the Count of Sussy, 1812 Dec. 31 (Box 3, Folder 146)
    Journu-Aubert explains the reason for which he could not attend his meeting with the Count and recommends his nephew, Bory, for a job at the ministry of Commerce.
  - Letter from Baron De La Bouillerie to Mr. Le Goux, 1812 Dec. 31 (Box 3, Folder 147)
    La Bouillerie asks Mr. Le Goux to be favorable with Mr. Dubois, who has just been nominated candidate for a post at the Tribunal.
  - Letter from Nicolas Marie Quinette to Mr. Dumont, 1813 Feb. 3 (Box 3, Folder 148)
    Quinette asks Mr. Dumont to let Mr. Moisson know that he has received the letter.
  - Letter from Garat, 1813 Feb. 4 (Box 3, Folder 149)
    Garat states that "his Majesty" may have doubts on his sincerity and loyalty, but he explains why that should not be the case.
  - Letter from Jean Bapt. Rob. Lindet to Mr. Legendre, 1813 Feb. 27 (Box 3, Folder 150)
    Lindet explains the legal situation that involves Mr. Legendre and assures him that he will receive his money.
  - Letter from V. Vansittart to d'Antraigues, 1813 Mar. 6 (Box 3, Folder 151)
    Vansittart compliments the Count and informs him that he will not be able to meet with him because of business.
  - Letter from Count De Croy, 1813 Mar. 8 (Box 3, Folder 152)
    Count De Croy explains the situation of the young Jochaud-Verdiere and hopes to find a place for him in the government school.
  - Letter from the Baron D'Arbaud-Jouques a Mr. St. Crieg, 1813 April 5 (Box 3, Folder 153)
    The Baron thanks Mr. St. Crieg for his letter and recommends Mr. Baussy for a position.
  - Document from the Count Rambuteau, prefect of Simplon, 1813 Jun. 28 (Box 3, Folder 154)
    The Count gives his signature as well as the Secretary General's in order to prove the authenticity of the document.
  - Letter from Joubert to the Count Sussy, 1813 Jul. 21 (Box 3, Folder 155)
    Joubert thanks the Count for his help with Mr. De La Grange and recommends Mr. d'Esparbay for a position.
  - Marriage Certificate from Jean Maury, Cardinal and Archbishop of Paris, 1813 Sept. 24 (Box 3, Folder 156)
    In Latin
  - Letter from Baron Mechin, Prefect of Calvador, 1813 Dec. 10 (Box 3, Folder 157)
    Baron Mechin explains that the list he had sent previously had not changed.
  - Letter from Conyere-Hamelinek to Mr. Collin, 1813 Dec. 18 (Box 3, Folder 158)
    Conyere-Hamelinek would like to fix the mistake he had previously made and recommends his brother to Mr. Collin
  - Letter from Baron Richard to Count Bergon, 1813 Dec. 24 (Box 3, Folder 159)
    Baron Richard asks for the opportunity to work with Count Bergon.
  - Letter from Arnoud Joubert to the Emporer Napoleon, 1813 Dec. 31 (Box 3, Folder 160)
    Joubert addresses his letter to HRH the Emperor Napoleon, expressing his gratitude for his past favors, but also explaining that his new position is a loss of dignity and requests a medal of honor in order to regain his dignity.
  - Letter from Amabert to Sussy, 1814 Mar. 12 (Box 3, Folder 161)
    Amabert requests with emergency a job for Mr. Director General who no longer has work.
  - Letter from P.P.N. Henrion de Pansey, Minister of Justice, to the Baron Le Goux, 1814 April 27 (Box 3, Folder 162)
    Henrion writes to the Baron explaining that his Royal Highness (probably Napoleon) has agreed to allow Sergent Major Kollarsk to be re-evaluated by the request of the Prince of Schwarzenberg.
  - Letter from Henri Evrard the Marquis de Dreux-Breze to M. de la Bouisse, 1814 Jul. 22 (Box 3, Folder 163)
    Dreux-Breze thanks M. de la Bouisse for his letter and sends him a book.
  - Letter from François the Marquis de Jaucourt, 1814 Sept. 23 (Box 3, Folder 164)
    Jaucourt explains to the addressee that the King (Louis XVIII) has ordered to pay him a provisional pension of 6000 francs per year for his services.
  - Letter from François Louis Auguste Frenier to the customs administration, 1814 Oct. 11 (Box 3, Folder 165)
    Frenier recommends a certain "Bernard" for a job
  - Letter from Charles Henry Danbray to M. Count Dupont, 1814 Nov. 23 (Box 3, Folder 166)
    Dambray, Chancellor of France under Louis XVIII, explains to the Count that S. Bannenberger, Protestant Minister in Vendenheim, has to pay a certain sum for committing a minor crime.
  - Letter from the Marquis de Beurnonville to Mr. Le Picard, 1814 Dec. 12 (Box 3, Folder 167)
    The Marquis de Beurnonville reiterates his request for his nephew, Mr. Etienne Martin de Beurnonville, to receive the title of Baron.
  - Letter from the Marquis de Jaucourt, Minister of Foreign Affairs, to the Baron Louis, 1815 Feb. 25 (Box 3, Folder 168)
    The Marquis de Jaucourt asks the Baron for an answer to a question posed months before.
  - Letter from Cadudal to Mrs. De Brecy, 1817 April 24 (Box 3, Folder 169)
    Cadudal asks Mrs. De Brecy about a job for Mr. Le Frotter
  - Letter from Alice de Brest to Mr. Pierquint, 1818 Sept. 28 (Box 3, Folder 170)
    De Brest explains that his mother is sick and requests Mr. Pierquint to write to le Marquis (we do not have his name)
  - Letter from the Baron Bruny to the Minister of Finance, 1819 Jun. 2 (Box 3, Folder 171)
    The Baron asks the minister to give him permission for (?)
  - Letter from Barante to "Mr. le Baron", 1820 Sept. 7 (Box 4, Folder 172)
    Barante explains why he did not take the post of minister in Denmark when it was offered to him.
  - Letter from Ant. Alexandre Barbier, to Mr. Peuchet, 1820 Nov. 12 (Box 4, Folder 173)
    Barbier informs Mr. Peuchet that the author of the book mentionned is Innocent Gentillod and is qualified as an "anti-Macchiavel".
  - Letter from the Duc of Dumas, 1821 April 29 (Box 4, Folder 174)
  - Letter from Benjamin Constant, 1821 Dec. 20 (Box 4, Folder 175)
    Constant proposes to add an article to the regulations
  - Letter from the Duke of York, 1823 Nov. 30 (Box 4, Folder 176)
    The Duke of York presents his compliments to De Beu(?)
  - Letter from Du Muy to Me. Cavillier, a furniture store owner, 1774 Jul. 13 (Box 4, Folder 177)
    Du Muy compliments Mr. Cavillier on his workmanship.
  - Letter from Du Muy, 1775 Jan. 9 (Box 4, Folder 179)
    [barely legible]
  - Letter from Miss Dionis, 1795 Mar. (Box 4, Folder 180)
    Miss Dionis explains that Mardi Gras is not a good meeting day
  - Letter from DuFrenoy to Mr. Emery, 1812 (Box 4, Folder 181)
  - Letter from Chateauneuf, 1816 April 17 (Box 4, Folder 181)
    Chateauneuf explains that he will continue to publish his work on Napoleon Bonaparte in London, and asks his addressee to copy the names of all of the subscribers and place it where others can see
  - Document from Jean Nicolas Bouilly, 1822 April 12 (Box 4, Folder 182)
    Bouilly explains that he has received what was sent to him.
  - Poem by Charles Cavenne, 1822 May 11 (Box 4, Folder 183)
    The poem concerns soldiers
  - Letter from Brun de Viller, 1822 Aug. 4 (Box 4, Folder 184)
    Brun de Viller explains that the young person he recommended when staying in Paris is ill at the moment, but the addressee of the letter should not lose interest in him.
  - Letter from Dumas de Lyon to the Doctor Dt. Marie, 1823 Oct. (Box 4, Folder 185)
    The letter discusses the literary contest that took place in 1793 and the poems received by the Royal Academy of Sciences, Literature and Art in Lyon.
  - Letter to the Baron of Barante, 1825 Sept. 2 (Box 4, Folder 186)
  - Letter from Andrieux to Morel, 1825 Oct. 22 (Box 4, Folder 187)
  - Letter from Bourguignon, 1827 May 4 (Box 4, Folder 188)
    Bourguignon conveys observations
  - Letter from Camperone to Mr. Mafey, 1829 Jun. 11 (Box 4, Folder 189)
    Camperone requests a dozen pamphlets from Mr. Mafey
  - Letter from the Duc of Doubeauville to Count de la Bourdoumais (?), 1829 Sept. 15 (Box 4, Folder 190)
    The Duc of Doubeauville suggests to the Count that his relative should become prefect now that the prefect of Charente has resigned.
  - Letter from the Duc of Plaisance to a baron, 1830 Sept. 3 (Box 4, Folder 191)
    The Duc of Plaisance recommends Mr. De Tremont for the position of prefect of the Vosges region.
  - Letter from Emerian to Caffarelli, 1834 May 22 (Box 4, Folder 192)
    Emerian recommends a person
  - Letter from Desfourneaux, 1834 Nov. 4 (Box 4, Folder 193)
    Desfourneaux explains that he has not reviewed he letters yet
  - Letter from the Minister of Education to John Spencer Smith, 1835 Oct. 5 (Box 4, Folder 194)
    The Minister informs John Spencer Smith that he has received the list of works and is willing to dedicated a few to him.
  - Letter from Charles François de Riffardeau, Duc de Riviere, to a Countess, Jul. 5 (Box 4, Folder 195)
    The Duc explains why he did not meet up with the Countess.
  - Unidentified document (Box 4, Folder 196)
  - A document from the General Administration of Forests to the Ministry of Finance, 1801/1802 Feb. 4 (Box 4, Folder 197)
    Count Joseph Bonaparte asks for permission to build a road that he has started on his own property.
- Manuscripts without the Bibliotheca Lindesiana bookplate, 1767-1863, (1 box)
  Series includes manuscripts and engravings, chiefly of the French Revolutionary and Napoleonic periods, that do not bear the "Bibliotheca Lindesiana" bookplate. These materials may have been part of Lindsay's collection or may have been merged with the collection by a later owner. For the most part, there are no transcripts of these manuscripts.
  Arranged chonologically.
  - Letter from Le Duc De Marchel to M. Duffier, 1767 April 20 (Box 4, Folder 198)
    A letter stating that a marriage has been accepted and the King (Louis XV) has allowed the groom to contact him.
  - Letter from unknown, Caen, 1780 Jan. 5 (Box 4, Folder 199)
  - Letter from Beaufort to the Tribunal of French Sergents, 1784 Jul. 28 (Box 4, Folder 200)
    Beaufort writes to the Tribunal expressing his thoughts on an event that took place in Parlement.
  - Letter from Prince Charles Maurice de Talleyrand to Duportuis (?), 1836 Dec. 24 (Box 4, Folder 201)
    Prince Talleyrand writes to Duportuis (?), who must be a caretaker of his house, since he asks him to fill the icebox with ice as soon as it hails.
  - Letter from Prince Charles Maurice de Talleyrand to M. Duton, 1789 Jan. 14 (Box 4, Folder 201)
    The Prince thanks M. Duton for the New Year wishes.
  - Document certifying residence of a Miss Corregeoles in the department of Vienne, 1792 Nov. 10 (Box 4, Folder 202)
    Signed by officials, witnesses, and Miss Corregeoles.
  - Two letters and an engraving of Charles Francis, Duke of Le Brun, 1799 (Box 4, Folder 203)
    One letter is addressed to Perregaux
  - Letter from the general governor of the Palace to Duroc, 1799 (Box 4, Folder 204)
  - Letter from Gerard Christophe Michel Duroc, Duc de Frioul, 1809 April 10 (Box 4, Folder 204)
  - Letter from Elgin (Thomas Bruce?) to M. Perregaux, 1804 Nov. 14 (Box 4, Folder 205)
    Elgin asks M. Perregaux to send a sum of twelve thousand Francs, and attaches a letter written by "Milady".
  - Administrative letter from Marec to M. Gaudin, Minister of Finance, 1807 Sept. 18 (Box 4, Folder 206)
    Marec discusses a law passed by the legislative branch to establish a new court.
  - Receipt of General Moreau, 1808 Sept. (Box 4, Folder 207)
  - Letter from Hugues-Bernard Maret, Duc de Bassano, Feb. 3 (Box 4, Folder 208)
  - Letter from M. Savary, Duke of Rovigo and Police Generale, to the Duke of Bassano, 1810 Jun. 8 (Box 4, Folder 208)
    Rovigo informs the Duc de Bassano that his interactions will remain the same as they were with his predecessor.
  - Engraving of M. Savary, Duke of Rovigo, undated (Box 4, Folder 208)
  - Letter from Marie Chamand, Countess de la Valette, 1813 Jul. 31 (Box 4, Folder 209)
  - Engraving of Marie Chamand, Countess de la Valette by S. Freeman, 1816 April 16 (Box 4, Folder 209)
  - Letter from the Marie Chamand, Countess de la Valette, to her Daughter, 1816 Jan.3 (Box 4, Folder 209)
    The Countess writes to her daughter in order to calm her down; she seems to be tormented however her mother explains that only God can protect them.
  - Letter from the Ministry of Police, 1826 (Box 4, Folder 210)
  - Engraving of Joseph Fouché, 1824 (Box 4, Folder 210)
  - Letter from Marie Joseph Paul Yve Roch, Marquis de Lafayette, to M. Jullien, 1827 Feb.26 (Box 4, Folder 211)
    The Marquis de Lafayette expresses thanks for the letter from M. Jullien, and agrees to meet with him the following day.
  - Letter from Gilbert-Augustin Thierry, undated (Box 4, Folder 212)
  - Letter from to the Baron Rothchild, undated (Box 4, Folder 213)
  - Letter from Prince Napoleon-Louis Bonaparte to Sir Hugh and Lady Campbell, May 15 (Box 4, Folder 214)
    The Prince presents compliments to Sir Hugh and Lady Campbell and accepts their invitation for dinner.
  - Letter, in English, possibly from François d'Orléans, Prince of Joinville, at Claremont, Surrey, to an unkown recipient, 1863 Jan. 25 (Box 4, Folder 215)